# **Benjamin Toll**

benjam72@yahoo.com http://benjamintoll.com https://github.com/btoll 717-756-2200

#### **SUMMARY**

DevOps professional with extensive engineering experience. Highly effective at creating tooling and full-stack applications. Significant experience with building both applications and frameworks.

Record of success working for top-tier technology organizations, both large and startups, including in Silicon Valley.

Communication and continued technical and personal growth is highly-valued. Skilled at requirements gathering, research, information assimilation and debugging.

#### LANGUAGES

Python, Bash shell scripting, JavaScript, Golang, C, PHP, Elm, Groovy

#### **TOOLS**

Linux System Administration, Jenkins, Ansible, Kubernetes, Helm, Docker, Vagrant, Make, Travis, AWS, GCP

## **Experience**

#### Consultant, Software Engineer and DevOps Princeton, MA

January 2016 – Present

Work with several clients to develop full-stack applications written in JavaScript/React, Elm and Golang with infrastructure in AWS and GCP. In addition, maintained Linux systems onpremise.

Deliver push button solutions that save clients countless hours every week.

#### Algorand, DevOps Engineer Boston, MA

November 2019 – February 2021

Responsible for package builds as well as maintaining in-house tools and Kubernetes build

- Built a fully-automated package build pipeline running in Jenkins in a Kubernetes cluster. Includes creation of deb and rpm packages, testing, signing and deploying to hosted mirrors. This saved engineers and product managers countless hours every time there was a deployment and allowed them to concentrate on other tasks.
- Maintain and improve in-house task runner written in Python. Added plugin support and other enhancements which further helped to automate and streamline build pipeline.
- Write tests and documentation

#### Sencha Inc, Frameworks Engineer Redwood City, CA

#### May 2013 - December 2015

Worked on the Ext framework as part of a remote team. My primary role was that of enhanced engineering.

- Fixed bugs that had been escalated by the Support team and/or by customer request.
- Patches (and tests) would then be merged into core.
- As the last stop in the escalation chain, worked on bugs that were very difficult and esoteric.
- Selected by manager to maintain viability of older product releases.
- One of the top framework contributors in the history of the company.

In addition, worked on new framework features and other projects within the company.

- Primary developer on the improved gridfilters API that shipped starting with Sencha 5.
- Resurrected the Sencha Fiddle project with my manager and developed several iterations of a working prototype before handing it off to its current maintainer.

Volunteered personal time to assist and mentor.

#### Sencha Inc, Senior Support Engineer

Redwood City, CA

#### June 2011 - April 2013

Hired when the department was first created and was the second support engineer added to the team. This was an engineering job and within the purview of the engineering department. All solutions were provided in code and patches to the framework were encouraged.

- Process support tickets generated by customers. This meant everything from answering general questions about the framework and web development to (more usually) providing patches to fix a specific problem.
- As a senior member of the team was one of three team members that would be assigned the difficult escalated tickets to resolve.
- Promoted to the Ext frameworks team.

In addition, did a lot of work that was not part of my role or expected of me as a support engineer to help the team and the company. Examples include writing and maintaining tools that were used not only by the team but across the company. These included git extensions and bash tools.

Volunteered personal time to assist and mentor.

### Yahoo!, Software Engineer Sunnyvale, CA

November 2009 - May 2011

Worked on the Connected TV team. JavaScript running on TVs.

- Developed new applications to run on networked TVs.
- Contributed to the KONtx framework.
- Principal maintainer of several high profile applications (eBay, NFL, Y! TV).
- Very active in forums.

Because there were no GUI devtools like that in the browser to help debug a program, became very good at thinking through problems and all iterations of them to try and anticipate bugs, which has helped tremendously in every role since.

#### GoDaddy, Web Developer Phoenix, AZ

January 2009 - November 2009

Worked on the ecommerce team as the sole frontend developer.

## **Education**

University of New Mexico, BA, History, 1996 - 1999

- 3.93 / 4.00
- summa cum laude
- Phi Beta Kappa
- Phi Alpha Theta